A Guide to the Office of Fraternity and Sorority Life, Office Administrative Files, 1990-2005
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Office of Fraternity and Sorority Life, Office Administrative Files 1990-2005
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
18/2/15.071
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
The files were transferred to the Library by the Office of Fraternity and Sorority Life, 2007 October 5.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of the Office of Fraternity and Sorority Life's administrative, alphabetical and topical files. Of interest is a scrapbook of clippings concerning Delta Upsilon and the Operation Equinox drug bust of 1991. The files also contain the University of Virginia Dr. Jerome H. Holland Medal awarded to Gilbert Jay Backers.
Arrangement
The files are arranged in seven series: Series I. Fraternal Organization Agreement Documentation; Series II. Sororities: Fraternal Organization Agreement Documentation; Series III. Multicultural Fraternities/Sororities: Fraternal Organization Agreement Documentation; Series IV. Fraternities: General Files; Series V. Sororities: General Files; Series VI. Multicultural Fraternities/Sororities-General Files; Series VII. Fraternity/Sorority Councils-General Files.
Contents List
- Series I: Fraternal Organization Agreement (FOA) Documentation
  - Fraternal Organization Agreement- General, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Alpha Delta Phi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Alpha Epsilon Pi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Alpha Tau Omega- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Beta Theta Pi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Chi Phi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Chi Psi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Delta Kappa Epsilon- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Delta Upsilon- FOA Documentation, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Delta Upsilon- FOA Documentation, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Kappa Alpha- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Kappa Sigma- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Phi Delta Alpha- FOA Documentation, 2000 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Phi Delta Theta- FOA Documentation, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Phi Gamma Delta- FOA Documentation, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Phi Kappa Psi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Phi Kappa Sigma- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Phi Sigma Kappa- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Pi Kappa Alpha- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Pi Kappa Phi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Pi Lambda Phi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Sigma Alpha Epsilon- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Sigma Alpha Mu- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Sigma Chi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Sigma Nu- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Sigma Phi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Sigma Phi Epsilon- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Sigma Pi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - St. Anthony Hall- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - St. Elmo Hall- FOA Documentation, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - St. Elmo Hall- FOA Documentation, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Theta Chi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 5:1a)
  - Theta Delta Chi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Zeta Beta Tau- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Zeta Psi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 5:4)
- Series II: Sororities - Fraternal Organization Agreement (FOA) Documentation
  - Alpha Chi Omega- FOA Documentation, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Alpha Delta Pi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Alpha Omicron Pi- FOA Documentation, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Alpha Phi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Chi Omega- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Delta Delta Delta- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 6:6)
  - Delta Gamma- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Delta Zeta- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Gamma Phi Beta- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Kappa Alpha Theta- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Kappa Delta- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Kappa Kappa Gamma- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Phi Mu- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Pi Beta Phi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 7:7)
  - Sigma Kappa- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 8:1)
  - Sigma Sigma Sigma- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 8:2)
  - Zeta Tau Alpha- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 8:3)
- Series III: Multicultural Fraternities/Sororities- Fraternal Organization Agreement (FOA) Documentation
  - Alpha Kappa Alpha- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Alpha Kappa Delta Phi- FOA Documentation, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Alpha Phi Alpha- FOA Documentation, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Delta Sigma Theta- FOA Documentation, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Kappa Alpha Psi- FOA Documentation, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 8:8)
  - Lambda Upsilon Lambda- FOA Documentation, 2000 (Box-folder 8:9)
  - Omega Phi Beta- FOA Documentation, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Omega Psi Phi- FOA Documentation, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Phi Beta Sigma- FOA Documentation, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Sigma Gamma Rho- FOA Documentation, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 9:4)
  - Zeta Phi Beta- FOA Documentation, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 9:5)
- Series IV: Fraternities- General Files
  - Alpha Delta Phi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 9:6)
  - Alpha Epsilon Pi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 9:7)
  - Alpha Tau Omega- General, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 9:8)
  - Beta Theta Phi- General, 1999 July - 2000 (Box-folder 9:9)
  - Beta Theta Phi- General, 1998-1999 April (Box-folder 9:10)
  - Chi Delta Sigma- General (Formerly Tau Epslion Phi), 1991-1992 (Box-folder 10:1)
  - Chi Phi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 10:2)
  - Chi Psi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 10:3)
  - Delta Kappa Epsilon- General, 1999 May - 2000 (Box-folder 10:4)
  - Delta Kappa Epsilon- General, 1998 - 1999 April (Box-folder 10:5)
  - Delta Sigma Phi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 10:6)
  - Delta Tau Delta- General, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 10:7)
  - Delta Upsilon- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 10:8)
  - Delta Upsilon, 1991, 1994 (Box-folder 10:9)
    Chiefly a scrapbook of 1991 clippings concerning a Drug Bust (copies).
  - Kappa Alpha- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 10:10)
  - Kappa Sigma- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 10:11)
  - Phi Delta Theta- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 10:12)
  - Phi Gamma Delta- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 11:1)
  - Phi Kappa Psi- General, 1999 (Box-folder 11:2)
  - Phi Kappa Psi- General, 1998 (Box-folder 11:3)
  - Phi Kappa Sigma- General, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 11:4)
  - Phi Sigma Kappa- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 11:5)
  - Phi Kappa Alpha- General, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 11:6)
  - Pi Kappa Phi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 11:7)
  - Pi Lambda Phi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 11:8)
  - Sigma Alpha Epsilon- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 11:9)
  - Sigma Alpha Mu- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 11:10)
  - Sigma Chi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 12:1)
  - Sigma Nu- General, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 12:2)
  - Sigma Phi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 12:3)
  - Sigma Phi Epsilon- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 12:4)
  - Sigma Pi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 12:5)
  - St. Anthony Hall (Delta Psi)- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 12:6)
  - St. Elmo Hall (Delta Phi)- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 12:7)
  - St. Elmo Hall (Delta Phi)- General, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 12:8)
  - Tau Kappa Epsilon- General, 1990-1999 (Box-folder 12:9)
  - Theta Chi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 13:1)
  - Theta Delta Chi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 13:2)
  - Zeta Beta Tau- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 13:3)
  - Zeta Psi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 13:4)
  - Alpha Tau Omega-Manual, [c. late 1990] (Box-folder 13:5)
- Series V: Sororities-General Files
  - Alpha Chi Omega- General, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 13:6)
  - Alpha Delta Pi- General, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 13:7)
  - Alpha Phi- General, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 13:8)
  - Alpha Xi Delta- General, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 13:9)
  - Chi Omega- General, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 13:10)
  - Delta Delta Delta- General, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 13:11)
  - Delta Gamma- General, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 14:1)
  - Delta Zeta- General, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 14:2)
  - Gamma Phi Beta- General, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 14:3)
  - Kappa Alpha Theta- General, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 14:4)
  - Kappa Delta- General, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 14:5)
  - Kappa Kappa Gamma- General, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 14:6)
  - Phi Mu- General, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 14:7)
  - Pi Beta Phi- General, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 14:8)
  - Sigma Kappa- General, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 14:9)
  - Sigma Sigma Sigma- General, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 15:1)
  - Zeta Tau Alpha- General, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 15:2)
- Series VI: Multicultural Fraternities/Sororities-General Files
  - Alpha Kappa Alpha- General, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 15:3)
  - Alpha Kappa Delta Phi- General, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 15:4)
  - Alpha Phi Alpha- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 15:5)
  - Delta Sigma Theta- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 15:6)
  - Kappa Alpha Psi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 15:7)
  - Lambda Phi Epsilon, 1997 (Box-folder 15:7a)
  - Omega Phi Beta- General, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 15:8)
  - Omega Psi Phi- General, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 15:9)
  - Sigma Gamma Rho- General, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 15:10)
  - Zeta Phi Beta- General, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 15:11)
- Series VII: Fraternity/Sorority Councils- General Files
  - Black Fraternal Council- General, 1993-1999 (Box-folder 15:12)
  - Black Fraternal Council- Membership Intake Process, 1989-1999 (Box-folder 15:13)
  - Fraternity Alumni Council, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 16:1)
  - Inter-Fraternity Council- General, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 16:2)
  - Inter-Fraternity Council- Executive Board, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 16:3)
  - Inter-Sorority Council- General, 1992-2005 (Box-folder 16:4)
  - Multicultural Greek Council- General, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 16:5)
  - University of Virginia Dr. Jerome H. Holland Medal awarded to Holland Scholar Gilbert Jay Backers, n.d., Artifact.